Brian Roepke

Product Management & Strategy | Design Thinking | Data Science

INTRODUCTION

I have led cross-disciplinary, global teams with compassion for more than twenty years, driving product and platform strategy together with engineering excellence. I am passionate about helping AEC and Manufacturing customers manage data and processes as a competitive advantage. I am an experienced platform thinker developing multi-sided markets and building a first-, second, and third-party ecosystems. I have built multiple successful businesses from zero and have transformed product organizations into modern product teams. I'm also passionate about diversity and inclusion and a curious, lifelong learner.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Data Analytics Product Management Design Thinking

Machine Learning Product Strategy Agile Methodologies

Team Culture & Leadership Public Speaking Cloud Computing

EXPERIENCE

AUTODESK

I spent my first fourteen years at Autodesk developing the Data Management strategy and businesses, eventually reporting to the SVP of Manufacturing after Autodesk acquired my startup. I transitioned to our horizontal cloud platform five years ago, where I drive strategy and lead a team of product people.

SR. DIRECTOR, HEAD OF PRODUCT, PLATFORM — 2016-2021

Led the creation of a multi-year strategy and roadmap for the cloud platform, including reusable capabilities, a differentiated data strategy, and a developer ecosystem.

- Raised customer trust in the platform by launching a SaaS Excellence program (Built With Forge) used by 4,000+ developers while scaling platform utilization 10x over 36 months.
- Grew developer ecosystem 300% over 36 months across second-and-third parties by identifying key use cases and extending platform capabilities to meet market needs.
- Led the creation of data services that currently manage 90% of Autodesk data.
- Transformed execution and operations, bringing a customer-centered "Platform as a Product" approach leveraging Scaled Agile and growing a Product organization of over 100 Product Managers, Designers, Researchers, Developer Advocates, and Data Analysts.

SR. DIRECTOR, PRODUCT LIFECYCLE MANAGEMENT — 2012-2016

Leader of product organization launching disruptive SaaS Product Lifecycle Management applications.

- Grew from 0 to 10,000+ Enterprise Users with 98% retention rates over 36 months.
- Grew Customer Accounts by 125% in 12 months via targeted Strategic Alliances.
- Led product strategy for five acquisitions across PLM, IoT, and Quote-to-Cash.
- Lead a team of 250 people through agile transformation, improving the ability to deliver software.

DIRECTOR OF PRODUCT MANAGEMENT, PORTLAND, OR — 2008-2012

Managed a \$50M product line with 250K users globally. Led the development of Go-to-Market strategies for Data Management applications in the Manufacturing space driving high growth in multiple strategic regions. Grew revenue 50%+ Y/Y. Grew channel partners selling the product line by 5x.

PRODUCT MANAGER, AUTODESK VAULT, PORTLAND, OR — 2002-2008

Grew Autodesk Vault through globally to 150K users. Built strategy for growth through freemium/bundled with up-sell to paid tiers. Drove product-market fit through rich relationships with stakeholders such as customers, direct and indirect sales leaders, and channel partners.

TRUEINNOVATIONS

PRESIDENT AND CEO, EAGAN, MN — 1999-2002

Founded a startup developing data/document management solutions for manufacturers. Identified an unmet market need and conceived and developed the product to address this need. Drove the asset acquisition with Autodesk in December of 2002. The flagship product became one of the most widely adopted products at Autodesk.

EDUCATION

- Golden Gate University, CA BS, Data Analytics, 2021, 4.0, Summa Cum Laude
- Saint Paul College, MN AA, Machine Tool & Die, 1995, 4.0

SKILLS

Languages: Python (scikit-learn, numpy, scipy, pandas, seaborn, matplotlib), R (tidyverse, dplyr, ggplot2, spacyr, tm, quanteda), SQL, Julia

Tools: GitHub, Docker, AWS, Snowflake, Tableau, dbt, Looker

CERTIFICATIONS

- <u>Certified Facilitator</u> of Human-Centered Design from LUMA Institute
- Digital Product Management from Boston University
- Data Science MicroMasters from UC San Diego
- Agile Project Management from University System of Maryland
- Site Reliability Engineering: Measuring and Managing Reliability from Google Cloud

419 Riviera Drive, San Rafael, CA, 94901 (415) 457-9222 broepke@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/broepke/ | https://github.com/broepke